

Hilla Klemetti

Master's level Information Networks student at Aalto University - majoring in User, Data & Design +358 50 320 2039

hilla.klemetti@aalto.fi

<u>hillaklemetti.me</u>

<u>Linkedin</u>

I enjoy ideation, problem solving and teamwork. I want to be creating better societies and ways of living. For that it's crucial to understand the role of technology and business design in today's society. I'm interested in socially and environmentally driven entrepreneurship, that thrives from collaboration in the intersection of research, technology and society.

Experience

Thesis worker

Jul 2023 - Jan 2024

Startup Foundation

Topic: Key aspects influencing research based startup creation in Finnish Universities.

Self Employed

Mar 2019 -

Personal Company

Concept design, website design, search engine optimisation, marketing, photography, videography, B2B customer survey reporting and translations.

Board Member & Jan 2021 - Dec 2021 Coordinator

Aalto Entrepreneurship Society

My responsibilities included managing 5+ projects, communications and community building of 200 members. I was also involved in project ideation, event organisation and podcast hosting to name a few.

Co-founder & Designer

Mar 2021 - Dec 2021

Wicked Helsinki

I was part of the founding team of an impact entrepreneurship community Wicked Helsinki. I was responsible for designing the brand identity, hosting meet-ups and other project management tasks

Sales & Marketing Aug 2016 - Sep 2020

Detalji boutique

I was responsible for sales, digital content creation, social media marketing and the newsletter. I also planned and executed styling, photoshoots and filming.

Education

Master of Science in Technology - ongoing

Aalto University 2022-2024

Bachelor of Science in Technology – graduated with honours

Aalto University 2018-2022

Exchange semester

Instituto Tecnológico y de Estudios Superiores de Monterrey (Mexico)

Spring 2022

Ylioppilas

Oulunkylän yhteiskoulu 2014–2018

Exchange year

Lycée Jacques Prévert (France) **2015-2016**

Skills

Design (services, concepts, strategies)
Data gathering & analysis
Project management
Problem solving
Prototyping
Teamwork
Facilitation
Communications
Community building

Finnish, English, French, Spanish, Swedish

Tools

Microsoft (PP, Excel, Word)
Miro
Figma
Adobe Softwares
Atlas.ti
SPSS
HTML, CSS, Scala
Data analytics with R

<u>References</u>

Josefiina Kotilainen

CEO of Startup Foundation contact details upon request

Nina Pyykönen

owner of Detalji boutique +358 40 513 7383

Mona Ismail

president of Aaltoes 2021 +358 45 206 9025